goldentours.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy | Golden Tours

### Introduction

Established in 1984, Golden Tours Ltd. are London’s sightseeing experts, providing top quality tours around the city and day trips to the best UK locations such as Stonehenge and Bath. With over 30 years of experience and an unrivalled range of top-quality London tours, they are proud to be in partnership with internationally renowned Gray Line Association and preferred partners of Warner Bros. Studio Tour London.

### What this privacy policy covers

Golden Tours Ltd. is committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with their obligations under data protection legislation. The current data protection law is found in the Data Protection Act 1998 but with effect from 25th May 2018, the main data protection law will be the General Data Protection Regulation as supplemented by the Data Protection Act 2018 and related laws.

This privacy policy explains what information Golden Tours Ltd. collects about you and how it will be used.

We, Golden Tours Ltd., ensure that any personal data shared with us or the personal data that we get from other organisations will be kept safe and will not be used for any purposes that you have not agreed to. Also, we want to inform you that any personal data we are collecting will be used for Golden Tours Ltd. purposes only and will not be shared with any third-party organisations.

If you have any concerns or queries regarding this privacy policy, please contact the Data Protection Lead on [dataprotection@goldentours.com](mailto:dataprotection@goldentours.com).

### Where and how we collect your information

We collect your information in the following ways:

  * Information you provide while you book or purchase any product(s) we sell at our outlets, online or through our approved resellers.
  * We will ask for your personal information in order to process your bookings or product(s) purchased on our Website, outlets, or resellers. This information may include but not limited to contact and address details, payments information and any other information required only for the purpose of completing your transaction.

We will highlight information collected automatically through our websites or apps. In this policy where we talk about our website, we are referring to websites owned by Golden Tours Ltd.

When we mention App, we are referring to Apps owned by Golden Tours Ltd.

### Cookies

We use cookies to enhance customer experience on our websites. Cookies means Golden Tours Ltd. website will remember you for a particular purpose and particular amount of time. To see our cookies policy, [click here](https://www.goldentours.com/cookie-policy).

A cookie is a simple text file that is stored on your computer or mobile device by a website's server and only that server will be able to retrieve or read the contents of that cookie. Each cookie is unique to your web browser. It will contain some anonymous information such as a unique identifier and the site name and some digits and numbers. When you access our websites or apps, your device will provide us some information such as type of device, operating system of device you are using or may report any details of website or app crash.

We also use a number of additional advertising cookies through tools that may change from time to time. However, these tools use a number of cookies to collect information and website usage statistics without personally identifying individual visitors to Golden Tours Ltd.

### Google Analytics

Golden Tours Ltd. uses Google Analytics to analyse the data but we do not collect any personal information. We use this tool to understand how our visitors are using and interacting with our website and apps. This analysis helps us to make improvements to our web services and your online experience.

### What information we collect and how we use it

Golden Tours Ltd. will collect information on you for different purposes outlined below:

  1. **Customers**

Golden Tours Ltd. collects and uses information that you provide to us. When you make a booking with us or with our business partners or alliances for any product(s) that we sell, you are (as a minimum) asked for Name, Email, Contact No, Address, Nationality and Payment information.

While you are getting in touch with our customer service team, to reach us through another avenue such as social media or communicating with your booked product on our site, we also collect information about you from there too. After using our services, customers can be asked to provide a review to help future customers get exactly what they are looking for.

There are also other instances where you will provide us with information. For example, if you’re browsing with your mobile device, you can enable our analytics to see your current location or grant access to your contact details – this helps us provide you with the best possible service. For example, next bus arrival times on our mobile app. You can also open a user account, which allows you to save your personal settings and plan and manage future reservations.

  2. **Other sources**

We may also receive information about you from other sources. These include business partners like affiliate partners and other independent third parties. Any data we receive from them might be combined with information provided by you.

Our affiliates and business partners are allowed to share information about you with Golden Tours Ltd. – this might happen if you have support questions about your pending reservation, when disputes arise about a booking or service, or there's any other communication about your bookings with us.

We use live chat software on our website, this is provided by Click4Assistance, a 3rd party UK based Software Company. Information regarding how the data is processed and stored can be viewed here. <https://www.click4assistance.co.uk/click4assistance-web-chat-software-cookie-policy>

  3. **Direct Marketing using email**

We will only contact you by email if you have given consent. By consenting to receiving Golden Tours Ltd. emails or opting in to email communications, you grant us permission to use your email address to send you email marketing communication.

Please note we may also use your information with data matching, data analysis or direct marketing platforms/companies to perform service on our behalf (for e.g. Google, Facebook, Instagram, other display advertising etc).

At any stage, you may choose to opt out of such communications.

  4. **Data Sharing**

Golden Tours Ltd. will not sell your data. We will not share your data for marketing purposes unless you have previously provided consent on our website, social media, agent portals or any other digital or document sources of Golden Tours Ltd. or its partners. Likewise, in some circumstances we may need to share your details with business partners or affiliates for processing your bookings.

We may transfer your personal data to locations outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) to service providers and group companies to process your personal data for purposes set above.

Where we transfer your personal data outside of the EEA we take all reasonably necessary steps to ensure that your data is treated securely and is not compromised.

  5. **Your choice**

You always have a choice as to whether and how you want to receive communications about our work, products and services. If you do not want us to use your contact details to contact you in the future, you can opt out anytime.

If you choose not to be contacted by us, we will never send you personalised marketing communications, but we will keep your details on a ‘suppression list’ to ensure you aren’t contacted.

  6. **Legal basis for processing your personal data**

**Performance of contract:** The use of your information may be necessary to perform the contract that you have with us. For example, if you use our services to make an online booking, we will use your information to carry out our obligation to complete and administer that booking under the contract that we have with you.

**Legitimate interests:** We may use your information for our legitimate interests, such as to provide you with the best suitable content of the website, emails and newsletters, to improve and promote our products and services and the content on our website, and for administrative, fraud detection and legal purposes.

**Consent:** We may rely on your consent to use your personal information for certain direct marketing purposes. You may withdraw your consent at any time by contacting us at the addresses at the end of this Privacy Statement.

  7. **Retention**

In accordance with European data protection laws, we hold your information for only as long as necessary for the purpose needed.

  8. **Under 18’s/Children**

The services offered by Golden Tours Ltd. are not directed at children under 18 years old. The use of any of our services is only allowed with the valid consent of a parent or a guardian. If we receive information from a child under 18 years old, we reserve the right to delete it.

  9. **Image rights**

When you embark on a Golden Tours Ltd. tour, you may have your photograph taken for marketing purposes. We will always ask for consent to photograph or video children.

If you consent to having your photo taken and used for marketing or PR purposes, we will hold your name, image and age (if applicable) on file for future re-use.

### How we keep your personal information secure

In accordance with European data protection laws, we observe reasonable procedures to prevent unauthorized access to, and the misuse of, personal data.

We use appropriate business systems and procedures to protect and safeguard the personal data you give us. We also use security procedures and technical and physical restrictions for accessing and using the personal data on our servers. Only authorized personnel are permitted to access personal data in the course of their work.

### Call Recording and Monitoring

Please be aware that calls to and from Golden Tours Limited may be recorded. We may use the call recordings to monitor our customer service for quality or compliance purposes, to check the accuracy of the information you provide us, for fraud prevention purposes, or to provide training to our staff. We will retain the call recordings for as long as reasonably necessary to perform such activities and then delete them. Any personal information obtained from you during the call will be treated in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

### Your right to your personal information

Under the General Data Protection Regulation, you have the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you. You also have the right to request that we erase any personal information we hold, where Golden Tours Ltd. has no compelling reason to continue processing this data.

If you wish to request this information, please contact [dataprotection@goldentours.com](mailto:dataprotection@goldentours.com). We will then send you a form which you will need to complete and send back to us by post. We will also require you to provide two forms of identification. Once we have received your information request and your identification, we will respond within one month.

### Updates to this privacy policy

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy. If we do make any significant changes to the way we collect and process your personal information, we will make this clear on the Golden Tours Ltd. website.

### Raising queries or concerns

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about data protection at Golden Tours Ltd. please contact our Data Protection team on [dataprotection@goldentours.com](mailto:dataprotection@goldentours.com).

Last updated: August -2019
